{
    "section": "Flight Plans and Flight Itineraries",
    "section_number": "9",
    "questions": [
        {
            "index": "01",
            "question": "The amount of fuel and oil carried on board any helicopter at the commencement of a day VFR flight must be sufficient, to provide for foreseeable delays having been considered, to fly to the destination aerodrome,",
            "answers": {
                "1": "and thereafter for 45 minutes at normal cruising speed.",
                "2": "then to a specified alternate and thereafter for 45 minutes at normal cruising speed.",
                "3": "and thereafter for 20 minutes at normal cruising speed.",
                "4": "then to a specified alternate and thereafter for 20 minutes at normal cruising speed."
            },
            "correctAnswer": "3",
            "help_link": "",
            "references": [
                "CARs 602.88 - Fuel Requirements",
                "TC AIM-RAC - Fuel Requirements"
            ]
        },
        {
            "index": "02",
            "question": "The amount of fuel carried on board any propeller-driven aeroplane at the commencement of a day VFR flight must be sufficient, having regard to the meteorological conditions and foreseeable delays that are expected in flight, to fly to the destination aerodrome",
            "answers": {
                "1": "and then fly for a period of 45 minutes at normal cruising speed.",
                "2": "and then fly for a period of 30 minutes at normal cruising speed.",
                "3": "then to a specified alternate aerodrome and then for a period of 45 minutes at normal cruising speed.",
                "4": "then to a specified alternate aerodrome and then fly for a period of 30 minutes at normal cruising speed."
            },
            "correctAnswer": "2",
            "help_link": "",
            "references": [
                "CARs 602.88 - Fuel Requirements",
                "TC AIM-RAC - Fuel Requirements"
            ]
        },
        {
            "index": "03",
            "question": "If a flight plan is not filed, a flight itinerary must be filed",
            "answers": {
                "1": "for flights proceeding 25 NM or more from the point of origin.",
                "2": "only for flights in sparsely settled areas.",
                "3": "for flights destined to land at aerodromes or places other than the point of origin.",
                "4": "for all flights."
            },
            "correctAnswer": "1",
            "help_link": "",
            "references": [
                "CARs 602.73 - Requirement to File a Flight Plan or a Flight Itinerary",
                "TC AIM-RAC - Flight Plans and Flight Itineraries, When Required"
            ]
        },
        {
            "index": "04",
            "question": "After landing from a VFR flight for which a flight plan has been filed, the pilot shall report the arrival to the appropriate ATS unit within",
            "answers": {
                "1": "15 minutes.",
                "2": "30 minutes.",
                "3": "45 minutes.",
                "4": "60 minutes."
            },
            "correctAnswer": "4",
            "help_link": "",
            "references": [
                "CARs 602.77 - Requirement to file an Arrival Report",
                "TC AIM-RAC - Closing a Flight Plan"
            ]
        },
        {
            "index": "05",
            "question": "When there is a deviation from a VFR flight plan, ATC shall be notified of such deviation",
            "answers": {
                "1": "as soon as possible.",
                "2": "within 10 minutes.",
                "3": "within 30 minutes.",
                "4": "within 60 minutes after landing."
            },
            "correctAnswer": "1",
            "help_link": "",
            "references": [
                "CARs 602.76 - Changes in a Flight Plan",
                "TC AIM-RAC - Changes to the Information in a Flight Plan or Flight Itinerary"
            ]
        },
        {
            "index": "06",
            "question": "Where no search and rescue initiation time is specified in a flight itinerary, when shall the pilot report to the “responsible person”?",
            "answers": {
                "1": "Within one hour after the expiration of the estimated duration of the flight specified in the flight itinerary.",
                "2": "Within one hour after landing.",
                "3": "Within 24 hours after the expiration of the estimated duration of the flight specified in the flight itinerary.",
                "4": "As soon as practicable after landing but no later than 24 hours after the last reported ETA."
            },
            "correctAnswer": "4",
            "help_link": "",
            "references": [
                "CARs 602.77 - Requirement to file an Arrival Report",
                "TC AIM-RAC - Closing a Flight Plan"
            ]
        },
        {
            "index": "07",
            "question": "With regard to a flight itinerary, the “responsible person” means an individual who",
            "answers": {
                "1": "has agreed to report the aircraft overdue.",
                "2": "is 18 years of age or over.",
                "3": "holds an aeronautical license.",
                "4": "has agreed to report the arrival of the aircraft."
            },
            "correctAnswer": "1",
            "help_link": "",
            "references": [
                "CARs 602.70 - Flight Preparation, Flight Plans and Flight Itineraries, Interpretation, TC AIM-RAC - Filing"
            ]
        },
        {
            "index": "08",
            "question": "Where a VFR flight plan has been filed, an arrival report must be filed by the pilot",
            "answers": {
                "1": "by advising an ATS unit.",
                "2": "at each intermediate stop and then reopened on take-off.",
                "3": "by parking the aircraft in close proximity to the tower.",
                "4": "except at airports served by a control tower in which case the controller will automatically file the arrival report."
            },
            "correctAnswer": "1",
            "help_link": "",
            "references": [
                "CARs 602.77 - Requirement to file an Arrival Report",
                "TC AIM-RAC - Closing a Flight Plan"        
            ]
        },
        {
            "index": "09",
            "question": "Estimated elapsed time A to B --------- 1 hour 15 minutes.<br>Estimated stopover time at B  --------- 30 minutes.<br>Estimated elapsed time B to C --------- 1 hour 20 minutes.<br><br>Using the above information, what time should be entered in the “Elapsed Time” box of a VFR flight plan?",
            "answers": {
                "1": "3 hours 50 minutes.",
                "2": "3 hours 20 minutes.",
                "3": "3 hours 05 minutes.",
                "4": "2 hours 35 minutes."
            },
            "correctAnswer": "3",
            "help_link": "",
            "references": [
                "TC AIM-RAC - Intermediate stops"
            ]
        },
        {
        "index": "10",
        "question": "When filing a VFR flight plan with an intermediate stop, the total elapsed time to be entered is the total",
        "answers": {
            "1": "elapsed time for all legs including the duration of the intermediate stop.",
            "2": "elapsed time for all legs, plus the intermediate stop, plus 45 minutes.",
            "3": "flight time for all legs.",
            "4": "elapsed time to the first landing plus intermediate stops."
        },
        "correctAnswer": "1",
        "help_link": "",
        "references": [
            "TC AIM-RAC - Intermediate stops"
        ]
        },
        {
        "index": "11",
        "question": "How is an intermediate stop indicated on the flight plan form for a VFR flight?",
        "answers": {
            "1": "By including duration of the intermediate stop in 'Elapsed Time' box as ATC automatically checks time between points.",
            "2": "Same as any VFR flight plan if the intermediate time does not exceed 30 minutes at each point.",
            "3": "By repeating the name of intermediate stop and its duration in the 'Route' column.",
            "4": "By simply indicating “Intermediate Stop” in “Other Information” column."
        },
        "correctAnswer": "3",
        "help_link": "",
        "references": [
            "TC AIM-RAC - Intermediate stops"
        ]
        }
    ]
}